diversalertnetwork.org 2003-06-21

# Divers Alert Network : Privacy Policy

Your Privacy  

DAN is committed to protecting your privacy and uses your personal information only to process orders and provide you with the highest level of service. Please read on for more details about DAN's policy regarding your privacy. 

What information do we collect? How do we use it? 

  * When you order a product or sign up for a membership, we need to know your name, e-mail address, mailing address, credit card number, and expiration date. This allows us to process and fulfill your orders and to notify you of your order status. 
  * When you enter a contest or other promotional feature, we may ask for your name, address, and e-mail address so we can administer the contest and notify winners. 
  * We also monitor traffic patterns and site usage to help us improve our site and identify problems. 
  * We may also use the information we collect to occasionally notify you about important functionality changes to our website, new DAN services, and announcements we think you will find valuable. 

How does DAN protect Member information? 

  * When you place an order or use our online membership form, we offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software (SSL) encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. Furthermore, all of the Member data we collect is protected against unauthorized access. 

What about "cookies"? 

  * "Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information, but they do enable us to learn more about our Members, provide better online features, and to store items in your shopping cart between visits. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that. Even without a cookie, you can still use most of the features on our site. However, we do not recommend this if you plan to purchase products or access restricted areas. 

Will DAN disclose the information it collects to outside parties? 

  * **DAN does not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others. As a DAN Member, you are eligible to apply for, or may receive, a number of benefits that are provided by companies other than DAN. To protect your privacy, DAN has very specific agreements with these companies that legally prevent the use of your personal information for any purpose other than the DAN Member benefit. For more information, please see below.**

Other than DAN, what companies provide DAN membership benefits? 

  * **MBNA America:** DAN Members are eligible to apply for the DAN/MBNA MasterCard credit card from MBNA America. Each time the card is used, DAN receives additional funding that supports its mission of improving dive safety. Although MBNA may contact existing DAN/MBNA MasterCard cardholders regarding their account, MBNA is legally prevented from using the Member’s information for any other purpose. If you do not want to receive information about the DAN/MBNA MasterCard, please contact DAN Membership Services at 1-800-446-2671 or +1-919-684-2948. 
  * **Palancar Industries:** DAN Members are eligible to purchase the DAN Tag™, which is manufactured by Palancar Industries. Palancar only receives what personal information the DAN Member voluntarily submits when ordering the product. DAN does not provide any additional information about a DAN Member to Palancar Industries. 

**In Summary**

  * DAN is committed to protecting your privacy. We use the information we collect on the site to enhance your overall experience while visiting DAN online. 

**Your Consent**

  * By using our website, you consent to the collection and use of this information by DAN. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

**Tell Us What You Think**

  * DAN welcomes your questions and comments about privacy. Please send e-mail to [webmaster@diversalertnetwork.org](mailto:webmaster@diversalertnetwork.org).
